iamempowered.com 2015-11-24

# Privacy Policy | iamempowered.com

Thank you for visiting this website. The National Urban League (“NUL” or “us” or “we”) values the protection of individual privacy. This privacy policy covers products, services and websites offered by NUL or its subsidiaries or affiliated companies collectively, NUL’s “services”, including the websites [www.nul.org](http://www.nul.org/); [www.iamempowered.com](http://www.iamempowered.com/); and [www.nationalurbanleaguestore.org](http://www.nationalurbanleaguestore.org/) (the “sites”). This Privacy Policy covers information that is collected when you use the services, including when you browse or log on to the sites.

By using the services, you the user (“you”) indicate that you have read and agree to be bound by this privacy policy. If you do not agree to this policy, do not use the services in any manner.

  1. **Introduction:**  
We are committed to the privacy of our visitors. We do not make any visitor-provided information available to third parties, except as disclosed below. Here is how we handle information about your visit to our sites and the use of our services:
  2. **Information collected and stored automatically:**  
We offer a number of services that do not require you to register for an account or provide any personal information to us. 

If you do nothing during your visit but browse through the sites, read pages, or download information, we will gather and store certain information about your visit automatically. In order to provide our full range of services, we may collect the following types of information:

    * The Internet domain (for example “abccompany.com”)
    * Your IP address (an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing on the Web) from which you access the sites
    * The type of browser and operating system you use to access the sites
    * The date and time you access the sites
    * The pages you visit within the sites
    * If you linked to our web site from another site, the address of that website

This information does not identify you personally. We may share with third parties certain pieces of [aggregated, non-personal information](http://www.google.com/privacy_faq.html#toc-terms-aggregated-info), such as the number of users who searched for a particular term, for example, or how many users clicked on a particular advertisement. Such information does not identify you individually. NUL only processes this information for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy for specific services. In addition to the above, such purposes include:

    * Providing our services, including the display of customized content and advertising;
    * Auditing, research and analysis in order to maintain, protect and improve our services;
    * Ensuring the technical functioning of our network;
    * Protecting the rights or property of NUL or our users; and
    * Developing new services.
  3. **Information that you voluntarily provide:**  
We receive personally identifiable information from you in connection with various services and web forms provided by us or our partners and affiliates on the sites. Submitting this personally identifiable information (such as your name, email address and an account password) constitutes your consent to the use of the information for the purpose stated. 
    * We collect personally identifiable information when you send an email or other communications or fill out a form. We may retain those communications in order to process your inquiries, respond to your requests and improve our services.
    * When you use certain services, such as our E-Store and our Donations page, we also request credit card or other payment account information which we maintain in encrypted form on secure servers.
    * We offer some of our services on or through other web sites. Personal information that you provide to those sites may be sent to us in order to deliver the service. We process such information under this Privacy Policy. The affiliated sites through which our services are offered may have different privacy practices and we encourage you to read their privacy policies.
    * We collect information when you interact with us through our I Am Empowered campaign (“IAE”) by services such as signing up on IAE Pledge Cards; signing up for an IAE account; downloading and installing the I’m Empowered Application; using and providing information on mingle sticks tm or other IAE tools and products.
    * We collect information when you sign up for an IAE account or other NUL service or promotion that requires registration, or when you download or enable any gadget, mobile applications or software from the sites. The information collected by us when you enable a gadget or other application is processed under this privacy policy.
    * We may make available third party applications, gadgets or other tools through the services. Information collected by the application, gadget or tool provider is governed by their privacy policies.
    * We may present links in a format that enables us to keep track of whether these links have been followed. We use this information to improve the quality of our search technology, customized content and advertising.
  4. **Use of Information:**

We use your personal information to be able to give you personalized service (for example, information about your local area or your favorite subjects); to provide you with the information and services that you request; to send you email alerts; to let you donate online, etc. You can easily opt-out at any time to stop any further contact with us. We also use it to track your and others’ use of our web site. This lets us see which of our features are the most popular so we can better serve our users’ needs. It also provides us aggregate data about our traffic (not identifying you personally, but showing how many visitors used which features, for example) to outside parties.

We may combine the information you submit under your account with information from other NUL services or third parties in order to provide you with a better experience and to improve the quality of our services. For certain services, we may give you the opportunity to opt out of combining such information.

If we become involved in a merger or acquisition, we will ensure the confidentiality of any personal information involved in such transactions and provide notice before personal information is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

  5. **Choices for Personal Information:**  
IAE is not just a website. It is also a service for sharing your information on enhanced social networking applications and websites. IAE is designed to make it easy for you to share your information with anyone you want. You decide how much information you feel comfortable sharing on IAE and you control how it is distributed through your privacy settings. You should review the default privacy settings and change them if necessary to reflect your preferences. You should also consider your settings whenever you share information. In addition, the affiliated sites through which our IAE services are offered may have different privacy practices and we encourage you to read their privacy policies. 

If we propose to use personal information for any purposes other than those described in this Privacy Policy, we will offer you an effective way to opt out of the use of personal information for those other purposes. You can decline to submit personal information to any of our services, in which case NUL may not be able to provide those services to you.

  6. **Links to other sites:**

The sites may contain links to various other sites. Once you link to another website, you are then subject to the privacy policies of the new website. We cannot control nor are we responsible for any third party collection or use or your personal information. It is always a good idea to read the privacy policy of any website you visit.

  7. **Children:**  
You must be least fourteen years old and a resident of the United States or its territories, and possessions to use the Services. There is no exception to this requirement. We do not knowingly collect any personal information from children under the age of 14 that fall within the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act and Rule. By your use of the application, you agree that you are either 18 years of age or older, or an emancipated minor, or possess legal parental or guardian consent, and that you are fully able and competent to understand and accept this Agreement as a binding contract and to abide by all Terms.
  8. **Security and Data Integrity:**  
We process personal information only for the purposes for which it was collected and in accordance with this Privacy Policy or any applicable service-specific privacy notice. We periodically review our data collection, storage and processing practices to ensure that we only collect, store and process the personal information needed to provide or improve our services or as otherwise permitted under this Privacy Policy. We take reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information we process is accurate, complete, and current, but we depend on our users to update or correct their personal information whenever necessary. 

We store your personally identifiable information on secure servers and employ commercially reasonable efforts to protect the security of the information, including through encryption methods. We also use other “anti-hacking” security measures and occasionally employ security consultants.

We regularly review our compliance with this Privacy Policy. Please feel free to direct any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy or our treatment of personal information by contacting us through this web site or by writing to us at

Privacy Matters  
c/o The National Urban League, Inc.  
120 Wall Street  
New York, NY 10005

Or visit us at <http://www.nul.org/contact-us>.

When we receive formal written complaints at this address, it is our policy to contact the complaining user regarding his or her concerns. We will cooperate with the appropriate regulatory authorities, including local data protection authorities, to resolve any complaints regarding the transfer of personal data that cannot be resolved between NUL and an individual.

  9. **Cookies:**  
We may use cookies from time to time to allow us to automate access and the data entry functions of the sites such as to tailor a site to your preferences or interests, customize promotions or marketing, or identify which areas of a site are more popular. A cookie is a small, unique text file that a website can send to your computer hard drive when you visit that site. We do not make any cookie information available to third parties. Most web browsers can either alert you to the use of cookies or refuse to accept cookies entirely. If you do not want us to deploy cookies in your browser, you can set your browser to reject cookies or to notify you when a website tries to put a cookie on your computer. Rejecting cookies may affect your ability to use some of the products and/or services at any site.
  10. **Accessing and updating personal information:**  
When you use the services, we make good faith efforts to provide you with access to your personal information and either to correct this data if it is inaccurate or to delete such data at your request if it is not otherwise required to be retained by law or for legitimate business purposes. We ask individual users to identify themselves and the information requested to be accessed, corrected or removed before processing such requests, and we may decline to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive or systematic, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others, or would be extremely impractical (for instance, requests concerning information residing on backup tapes), or for which access is not otherwise required. In any case where we provide information access and correction, we perform this service free of charge, except if doing so would require a disproportionate effort. Some of our services have different procedures to access, correct or delete users’ personal information. We provide the details for these procedures in the specific privacy notices or FAQs for these services. 

For general inquiries, please contact us at the address below:

Privacy Matters  
c/o The National Urban League, Inc.  
120 Wall Street  
New York, NY 10005

Or visit us at <http://www.nul.org/contact-us>.

  11. **Privacy Policy Changes:**  
We reserve the right to change this policy at any time at our sole discretion and without notice to you. All Privacy Policy changes are effective immediately. Each version of this Privacy Policy will be identified at the top of the page by its effective date. Your continued use of the sites following any policy changes will mean you accept those changes. 

Please contact us at the address below for any additional questions about the management or use of personal data.

Privacy Matters  
c/o The National Urban League, Inc.  
120 Wall Street  
New York, NY 10005

Or visit us at <http://www.nul.org/contact-us>.
